Sam Clark

<u>Sam.clark48@hotmail.co.uk</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

Sutton, Greater London

Profile

Highly motivated and organised software engineering graduate with experience developing front-end and back-end solutions using Java, Kotlin, TypeScript, React and more; with extensive knowledge of object-oriented development, effective design patterns and agile project management utilised during my studies and personal projects.

Education

Software Engineering BEng Honours

Sep 2021 - Jun 2024

University of Westminster – First Class Honours

- Developed several projects using Java, Kotlin, Swift, React.js & more.
- Achieved consistently high results across modules
- Member of the British Computing Society (BCS)

OCR Level 3 Cambridge Technical Diploma in IT

Sep 2017 - Jun 2019

Carshalton College & Merton College - Distinction* Distinction*

GCSE

Sep 2015 – Jun 2017

Sutton College

• Mathematics at Grade C | English at Grade 5

Employment

Retail Assistant

Jul 2024 – Present

Primark, Kingston Upon Thames & Sutton

Apr 2022 – Oct 2022

- Provided customers with great service on both the shop floor and on tills.
- Ensured that sections of the shop floor were tidy and maintained across the shift.
- Handled sorting of customer returns and redistribution onto the shop floor

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Java, Kotlin, TypeScript, JavaScript, Swift, C#, HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL

Frameworks: React, Next.js, Sass, Bootstrap, Spring Boot, Electron.js **Databases:** MySQL, SQLite, MariaDB, Firebase, Google Firestore

Software: IntelliJ, Android Studio, WebStorm, Rider, VS Code, Visual Studio 2022, CoScreen **Other:** Model-View-ViewModel (MVVM), Controller-Service-Repository (CSR), REST APIs, CI/CD,

Git, GitHub, Semantic Versioning, Conventional Commits, Pair Programming, KanbanFlow, Trello.

Projects

L2J Server Web API

Collaborative Project

Java Spring & MariaDB

- Co-development of an API based on data from a game server, with appropriate endpoints.
- Retrieves and parses game data from MariaDB relational database, XML and TSV files.
- Uses a Controller-Service-Repository pattern to ensure separation of concerns.
- Experience submitting pull requests with conventional commits structure.
- Gained experience participating in pair-programming sessions.

Web Scraper & Discord Bot

Personal Project

Java, MySQL & Discord4J

- Web scraper application retrieves most recent news feed posts by parsing website HTML data
- Discord bot application utilises the web scraper application along with Discord4J and MySQL
- Bot stores post data from previously retrieved posts and periodically checks for new posts through web scraper functionality, embedding new posts onto specified discord channels.

Just the News

Personal Project

Kotlin & Firebase

- Developed an Android-based news application using Kotlin & Firebase.
- Provided clear UI/UX design through use of DrawerLayout, RecyclerView & more.
- Implemented location services to retrieve news based on the user's location if the country is supported by the News API service, as well as option to manually set country.
- Utilised Firebase to store user account data upon account creation and for authentication when logging in, as well as other persistent data needs such as the user setting their location.
- Included support for Google Login functionality.

Digital eCommerce Games Media Application

Final Year Project

TypeScript, React.js, CSS, Node.js, Electron & SQLite

- Developed a digital eCommerce application using React.js & Electron framework.
- Utilised IGDB API service to retrieve game product data in JSON format.
- Included an account system with functionality to login, add products to basket and checkout, see recently viewed products and more.
- Ability for user to search by name or genre, as well as see new or upcoming releases.
- Library section for user to view products that they purchased (no payment processing included) and filter by genre and sort alphabetically.

References

References available upon request.